LINDSAY NEAL

www.lindsaykneal.com

913 226 1398

neal1191@gmail.com

EDUCATION

University of Kansas

Aug 2009 -Dec 2013

Bachelor of Science in Journalism, Strategic Communication emphasis.

Minor in Psychology, with additional courses in Business.

Johnson County Community College

Dec 2013 - Dec 2015

Associate of Applied Science in Web Development and Digital Media.

Concentration in Desktop Publishing.

OVERVIEW OF SKILLS

Skilled at creating strategic planning and advertising executions; conducting and documenting research; crafting blog and social media posts; writing and producing print ads and news releases; developing user guides and web governance documents.

Experienced at designing and developing websites; creating digital content, both written material and visual graphics.

Strong understanding of graphic design concepts, user experience design and user interface design, as well as search engine optimization and analytics.

Proficient with Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, and InDesign. Ability to plan and project ideas and experiences with visual and textual content.

Experience with content management systems (Wordpress, Drupal), CSS frameworks (Bootstrap) and version control systems (Git). Core languages: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, Ajax.

EXPERIENCE

Web Designer - SoftScience Group, Inc., Jun 2015 - present

Utilized front-end coding skills to build and develop core company websites and other client websites. Produced UI/UX design wireframes and mock-ups. Researched and employed current SEO techniques; evaluated site anaytics. Developed digital content, written and visual (graphics, logos, images, brochures).

Cake Artist/Owner - Sweet Nothings Cakes, Aug 2009 - present

Founded a specialty cake design and production, part-time business as a creative outlet. Dozens of happy, well fed clients. Created a company blog to attract customers.

Barista - Caribou Coffee, Dec 2013 - Jun 2015

Demonstrated ability to multi-task: engaging with customers while preparing drinks, cleaning, cash handling, stocking and other duties, such as training new hires. Opened and closed the store independently.

Bakery Assistant - Hy-Vee, Inc., Aug 2010 - Dec 2013

Prepared and stocked product. Greeted and assisted guests in a professional manner. Closed the store independently; trained and managed new hires.

ACTIVITIES

Lead To Read

Serve KC

JoCo DEMS

Reader - Spend one day a week reading with a 1st grader to improve basic reading skills. Member - Volunteered for non-profits such as the Ronald McDonald House, Harvesters, and Giving The Basics.

Communications Committee - Created a blog and promotional materials (handouts and signs).